Register of the Štefan Osuský Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1916-1971. (Box 32-68)
  - "Dr. Osuský a Goebbelsovi Učnovia," n.d. (Folder 45: 23)
  - "Droit slave," n.d. (Folder 45: 24)
  - "Due Process of Law," n.d. (Folder 45: 25)
  - "Economic Collaboration," n.d. (Folder 45: 26)
  - "Economic Elements," n.d. (Folder 45: 27)
  - "Economist and Historian," n.d. (Folder 45: 28)
  - "Egypt," n.d. (Folder 45: 29)
  - "The Essential Russia," n.d. (Folder 45: 30)
  - "Europe and Russia," n.d. (Folder 45: 31)
  - "Europe: Historical Background," n.d. (Box-folder 46: 1)
  - "Europe's Integration and the Marshall Plan," n.d. (Folder 46: 2)
  - "Evakuacia," n.d. (Folder 46: 3)
  - "The Failure of Britain's Negotiations to Enter the Common Market," n.d. (Folder 46: 4)
  - "Fascism and Liberty," n.d. (Folder 46: 5)
  - "Faustus Must Be Damned: The Tragic Story of Doctor Beneš," n.d. (Folder 46: 6)
  - "Federalism," n.d. (Folder 46: 7)
  - "Federalists and Carolingians," n.d. (Folder 46: 8)
  - "Federalization the Battle-Cry of Our Times," n.d. (Folder 46: 9)
  - "Feierabend," n.d. (Folder 46: 10)
  - "Feodor Dostoevskii," n.d. (Folder 46: 11)
  - "Feudal System," n.d. (Folder 46: 12)
  - "Fifth and Fourteenth Ammendments: Against Government Police-Power," n.d. (Folder 46: 13)
  - "The Financial Situation of the Czechoslovak Republic," n.d. (Folder 46: 14)
  - "Finsko-sovětská válka," n.d. (Folder 46: 15)
  - "For Good as for Evil," n.d. (Folder 46: 16)
  - "For Whom Does the Time Work?" notes on Winston Churchill's address at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Boston on March 31, 1949, n.d. (Folder 46: 17)
  - "Forced Labour Camps in Czechoslovakia," n.d. (Folder 46: 18)
  - "Foreign Affairs," n.d. (Folder 46: 19)
  - "Foreign Trade," n.d. (Folder 46: 20)
  - "The Founder of Slavophilism," n.d. (Folder 46: 21)
  - "France," n.d. (Folder 46: 22)
  - "France and Soviet Russia," n.d. (Folder 46: 23)
  - "František Němec in Subcarpathic Russia," n.d. (Folder 46: 24)
  - "Freedom: Common Standard of Morality," n.d. (Folder 46: 25)
  - "Freedom the Allies Are Fighting For," n.d. (Folder 46: 26)
  - "La frontière atlantique de l'Europe," n.d. (Folder 46: 27)
  - "Future Aspects of Central and Eastern Europe," n.d. (Folder 46: 28)
  - "The Future of Central Europe," n.d. (Folder 46: 29)
  - "The Future of the Danubian Basin," n.d. (Folder 46: 30)
  - "General Aims and Objects of the Allied Circle," n.d. (Folder 46: 31)
  - "General Ingr," n.d. (Folder 46: 32)
  - "General Kazimierz Sosnkowski," n.d. (Folder 46: 33)
  - "General Milan Rastislav Štefánik," n.d. (Folder 46: 34)
  - "German Tragedy," n.d. (Folder 46: 35)
  - "The Germans and the Transfer of Populations," n.d. (Folder 46: 36)
  - "Germany," n.d. (Folder 46: 37)
  - "Germany and Europe's Independence," radio broadcast, n.d. (Box-folder 47: 1)
  - "Germany, Russia and the Future: Mac Curdy," n.d. (Folder 47: 2)
  - "Germany's Moral Blackout," n.d. (Folder 47: 3)
    Notes and holograph
  - "The Goal of Soviet Policy," n.d. (Folder 47: 4)
  - "Gottwald's Affirmation of Stalin's Unconditional Support of CS," n.d. (Folder 47: 5)
  - "The Great Communist Leader Mao-Tse-Tung," n.d. (Folder 47: 6)
  - "La guerre et le monde slave," n.d. (Folder 47: 7)
  - "Hegel's Philosophy of State," n.d. (Folder 47: 8)
  - "The Historical Origin of the Unification of National Varieties in East-Central Europe," n.d. (Folder 47: 9)
  - "Hitler and His Political System," n.d. (Folder 47: 10)
  - "Horšie než vojna," n.d. (Folder 47: 11)
  - "Hospodářské ozdravění Evropy," n.d. (Folder 47: 12)
  - "The Hungarian Peace Delegation and the Treaty," n.d. (Folder 47: 13)
  - "Impeachment of Dr. Beneš," n.d. (Folder 47: 14)
    Holograph and typescript (in English and Slovak; text in Slovak is incomplete)
  - "Imponderables in History," n.d. (Folder 47: 15)
  - "The Importance of Jugo-Slavia," n.d. (Folder 47: 16)
  - "Industrial Strength of the Czechoslovak Republic," n.d. (Folder 47: 17)
  - "Industrialism and Education," n.d. (Folder 47: 18)
  - "The Influence of Stalin's Doctrine of Nationality on Small Slav Nations," n.d. (Folder 47: 19)
  - "Integration in Education," n.d. (Folder 47: 20)
  - "Integrovanie Europy," n.d. (Folder 47: 21)
  - "The Intellectual Awakening," n.d. (Folder 47: 22)
  - "International Collaboration and Small Nations," n.d. (Folder 47: 23)
  - "Introduction," n.d. (Folder 47: 24)
  - "Invasion of Europe and Military Defeat of Germany," n.d. (Folder 47: 25)
  - "Is Peace Between the United States and the Soviet Union Possible?" n.d. (Folder 47: 26)
  - "Is the Present Moment Appropriate to Define Allied War Aims?" n.d. (Folder 47: 27)
  - "Islamism and Orthodoxy," n.d. (Folder 47: 28)
  - "Jan Masaryk," n.d. (Folder 47: 29)
  - "Jeffersonian Democracy," n.d. (Folder 47: 30)
  - "Juri F. Samarin," n.d. (Folder 47: 31)
  - "Key to Soviet Failure in Korea," n.d. (Folder 47: 32)
  - "Khrushchev and Communist Encirclement," n.d. (Folder 47: 33)
  - "Kossuth a Beneš," n.d. (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - "The Kremlin's Actual Policy," n.d. (Folder 48: 2)
  - "The Labor Party: Historical Background," n.d. (Folder 48: 3)
    Typescript (incomplete)
  - "The Law of Contract in Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Poland and Romania," lecture under the auspices of the Foreign Law Association, Congressional Library, Washington, D.C., n.d. (Folder 48: 4)
  - "The Law of the Land," n.d. (Folder 48: 5)
  - "Lebanon," n.d. (Folder 48: 6)
  - "A Lecture in the Recent History of the Czechoslovakian Republic," n.d. (Folder 48: 7)
  - "Legal Position of Dr. Beneš, of the Šrámek Government and the Czechoslovak State Council," n.d. (Folder 48: 8)
  - "Leninism," n.d. (Folder 48: 9)
  - "Leopold Schwarzenhield: Prime of the Coming World in France," n.d. (Folder 48: 10)
  - "Lesson to the Free," n.d. (Folder 48: 11)
  - Letters to the editor, The Daily Worker, n.d. (Folder 48: 12)
  - "Liberty: The Soul of European Civilization," n.d. (Folder 48: 13)
  - "The Logic of Contradiction or the Logic of Dynamism," n.d. (Folder 48: 14)
  - "Londýnské štátné zriadenie," n.d. (Folder 48: 15)
  - "Ludwig Kossuth: A Revolutionary Leader," n.d. (Folder 48: 16)
  - "M. R. Štefánik," n.d. (Folder 48: 17)
    Notes and typescript (in French)
  - "Magyarization," n.d. (Folder 48: 18)
  - "Les Magyars et la Pologne," n.d. (Folder 48: 19)
  - "Man Lives by Imagination," n.d. (Folder 48: 20)
  - "Manufacturers of Illusions: Communist Party and Catholic Church Both Alike, Claim Czech National Socialists," n.d. (Folder 48: 21)
  - "Mao and the West," n.d. (Folder 48: 22)
  - "Marxism or Russian Communism," n.d. (Folder 48: 23)
  - "Marxist Philosophy," n.d. (Folder 48: 24)
  - "Masaryk, le réaliste," n.d. (Folder 48: 25)
  - "Masarykovy rozhovory s Čapkem," n.d. (Folder 48: 26)
  - "May First," n.d. (Folder 48: 27)
  - "Mechanism of the Disrupting Activities of the Germans in Preparation for 15th March 1939," n.d. (Folder 48: 28)
  - Memoirs (unfinished and unpublished), n.d. (Box-folder 49: 1-12)
  - Memorandum on Czechoslovakia's role in Central Europe, n.d. (Box-folder 50: 1)
  - "The Middle Zone Union," n.d. (Folder 50: 2)
  - "Milioukoff et les Cadets," n.d. (Folder 50: 3)
  - "Ministr Slavík," n.d. (Folder 50: 4)
  - "Mír, který by byl prohrou," n.d. (Folder 50: 5)
  - "The Miracle of Mind," speech, n.d. (Folder 50: 6)
  - "Misery of Soviet Victory," n.d. (Folder 50: 7)
  - "Le modèle soviétique," n.d. (Folder 50: 8)
    Typescript (of intended book?)
  - "Mohammed's Flight to Medina," n.d. (Folder 50: 9)
  - "Moje stanovisko k dr. Ed. Benešovi," n.d. (Folder 50: 10)
  - "Muj pobyt na lodi s rodinou," n.d. (Folder 50: 11)
  - "The Munich Agreement and Its Consequences for the Czechoslovak Republic," n.d. (Folder 50: 12)
  - "[Russian] Music - Poetry," n.d. (Folder 50: 13)
  - "Mysticism," n.d. (Folder 50: 14)
  - "Nazism and Liberty," n.d. (Folder 50: 15)
  - "The National Awakening," n.d. (Folder 50: 16)
  - "National Liberty Versus National Uniformity," n.d. (Folder 50: 17)
  - "NATO: Allied Defense and American Strategy," n.d. (Folder 50: 18)
  - "The Nature of American Spirit," n.d. (Folder 50: 19)
  - "The Nature of Chinese Communism," n.d. (Folder 50: 20)
  - "Needed: American Revolution in Countries Behind the Iron Curtain," n.d. (Folder 50: 21)
  - "Needed: An American Revolution," n.d. (Folder 50: 22)
  - "Nehynúca skutočnost o vzniku ČSR," Demokracie v exilu, n.d. (Folder 50: 23)
    Printed copy
  - "Německo-sovětský pakt o neútox010D;ení," n.d. (Folder 50: 24)
  - "Není třeba mluvit," n.d. (Folder 50: 25)
  - "Neutral Source on the Slovak Rising," n.d. (Folder 50: 26)
  - "The New Order," n.d. (Folder 50: 27)
  - "The New Ruling Class," n.d. (Folder 50: 28)
  - "The New Shift in the Soviet Policy," n.d. (Folder 50: 29)
  - "The New Soviet Man," n.d. (Folder 50: 30)
  - "The New World," n.d. (Folder 50: 31)
  - Notes, n.d.
    Holographs unless otherwise noted
    - Beard, Charles Austin, An Economic Interpretation of the Constitution of the United States (Folder 51: 1)
    - Becker, Carl Lotus, The Declaration of Independence (Folder 51: 2)
    - Beloff, Max, The Foreign Policy of Soviet Russia,1929-1941 (Folder 51: 3)
    - Beluš, Slovak Factor in Czechoslovak Evolution (Folder 51: 4)
    - Beneš's private conversations with American Ambassador, W. E. Dodd (Folder 51: 5)
    - Beveridge, William, Sir, The Price of Peace (Folder 51: 6)
    - Brod, Toman - Čejka, Eduard, Na západní frontě (Folder 51: 7)
    - Bryce, James, The Holy Roman Empire (Folder 51: 8)
    - Butler, Rohan d'Olier, The Roots of National Socialism (Folder 51: 9)
    - Butterfield, Herbert, The Statecraft of Machiavelli (Folder 51: 10)
    - Callender, Harold, A Preface to Peace (Folder 51: 11)
    - Cameron, Elizabeth R., Prologue to Appeasement: A Study in French Foreign Policy (Folder 51: 12)
    - Carr, Edward Hallett
      - The Bolshevik Revolution, 1917-1923 (Folder 51: 13)
      - Conditions of Peace (Folder 51: 14)
      - Nationalism and After (Folder 51: 15)
    - Churchill and France: Betrayal of the Small Nations (Folder 51: 16)
    - Constitutional presidency (Folder 51: 17)
    - Coulondre, Robert, De Staline à Hitler: Souvenirs de deux ambassades,1936-1939 (Folder 51: 18)
    - The Council of Mutual Economic Aid (Folder 51: 19)
    - Crankshaw, Edward, Soviet Union (Folder 51: 20)
    - Darwinism (Folder 51: 21)
    - Duroselle, J. Baptiste, From Wilson to Roosevelt: Foreign Policy of the United States,1913-1945 (Folder 51: 22)
    - Eisler, Pavel, Munich: A Retrospect (Folder 51: 23)
    - Eliot, Thomas Stearns, Notes Towards the Definition of Culture (Folder 51: 24)
    - Feierabend, L., The Problems of Central Europe: Czechoslovakia and Central European Reconstruction (Folder 51: 25)
    - Foerster, F. W., Europe and the German Question (Folder 51: 26)
    - Frantz, Constantin, Das grössere Deutschland (Folder 51: 27)
    - Galbraith, John K., The Great Crash:1929 (Folder 51: 28)
    - Gottmann, Jean, La politique des états et leur géographie (Folder 51: 29)
    - Hagemeyer, Hans, Europas Schicksalskampf im Osten (Folder 51: 30)
    - Halasz, Nicholas, In the Shadow of Russia: Eastern Europe in the Postwar World (Folder 51: 31)
    - Heer, Friedrich, Koexistenz, Zusammenarbeit, Widerstand: Grundfragen europäischer und christlicher Einigung (Folder 51: 32)
    - Jesin, P., K sedmdesátým narozeninám Eduarda Beneše (Folder 51: 33)
    - Jouvenel, Bertrand de, L'art de la conjecture (Folder 51: 34)
    - Klein, Burton H., Germany's Economic Preparations for War (Folder 51: 35)
    - Kraus, Dr., Osuský Is Unknown in Slovakia (Folder 51: 36)
    - Kutnár, František, Palackého pojetí společnosti, národa a státu (Folder 51: 37)
    - Lastovička, B., V Londýne za války zápasy o novou ČSR (Folder 52: 1)
    - Lazareff, Pierre, De Munich à Vichy (Folder 52: 2)
    - Legras, Jules, L'âme russe (Folder 52: 3)
    - Lichner, Zpráva o Slovensku (Folder 52: 4)
    - Mansergh, Nicholas, Survey of British Commonwealth Affairs: Problems of External Policy,1931-1939 (Folder 52: 5)
    - Mantoux, Etienne, The Carthaginian Peace (Folder 52: 6)
    - Masaryk, T. G., Česká otázka (Folder 52: 7)
    - Namier, Lewis Bernstein, Europe in Decay: A Study in Disintegration,1936-1940 (Folder 52: 8)
    - Nicolson, Harold, Peace Making,1919 (Folder 52: 9)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, Nature and Destiny of Man: A Christian Interpretation (Folder 52: 10)
    - Nove, Alec, Was Stalin Really Necessary? (Folder 52: 11)
    - Oakley, Hilda D., Should Nations Survive? (Folder 52: 12)
    - Parrington, V. L., Main Currents in American Thought (Folder 52: 13)
    - Plekhanov, Georgii Valentinovich, The Role of the Individual in History (Folder 52: 14)
    - Price, G. Ward, Year of Reckoning (Folder 52: 15)
    - Renouvin, Pierre, Introduction à l'histoire des relations (Folder 52: 16)
    - Riess, Curt, The Self-Betrayed: Glory and Doom of the German Generals (Folder 52: 17)
    - Rostow, Walt Whitman, The Stages of Economic Growth: A Non-Communist Manifesto (Folder 52: 18)
    - The Royal Institute of International Affairs Study Group
      - Political and Strategic Interest of the U.K.: An Outline (Folder 52: 19)
      - Survey of International Affairs 1939-1946: The Eve of War: 1939 (Folder 52: 20)
    - Russell, Bertrand, The Meaning of Marx (Folder 52: 21)
    - Schuman, Frederick Lewis
      - Europe on the Eve: The Crises of Diplomacy, 1933-1939 (Folder 52: 22)
      - Soviet Politics at Home and Abroad (Folder 52: 23)
    - Spender, John Alfred, Between Two Wars (Folder 52: 24)
    - Stendhal, Marie Henri Beyle, Le rouge et le noir (Folder 52: 25)
    - Suarez, Georges, Agonie de la paix,1935-1939 (Folder 52: 26)
    - Taylor, A. J. P., 1906 - From Napoleon to Stalin: Comments on European History (Folder 52: 27)
    - Temperley, H. W. V., A History of the Peace Conference of Paris (Folder 52: 28)
    - Tunkin, G. I., Foundations of Modern International Laws (Folder 52: 29)
    - Wallis, Robert, Time: 4th Dimension of the Mind (Folder 52: 30)
    - Warriner, Doreen, Eastern Europe After Hitler (Folder 52: 31)
    - Wildgans, Anton, Rede über Osterreich (Folder 52: 32)
    - Zimmern, Alfred, The Third Empire (Folder 52: 33)
  - Note on France being ignorant of the danger of Soviet communism, n.d. (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - Note on lecture of Dr. Lettrich, n.d. (Folder 53: 2)
  - "Notes on My Sojourn in Switzerland, October 1917 - November 1918," n.d. (Folder 53: 3)
  - Note on the Treaty of Rapallo, 1920, n.d. (Folder 53: 4)
  - "Notes on Centralization and Decentralization from the Angle of Liberty," n.d. (Folder 53: 5)
  - Notes on Geopolitics, n.d. (Folder 53: 6-7)
  - Notes on Great Britain, n.d. (Folder 53: 8)
  - "Nová americká revolučná politika," n.d. (Folder 53: 9)
  - "Nová Demokracie," n.d. (Folder 53: 10)
  - "Nová Evropa se rodí," n.d. (Folder 53: 11)
  - "Novomesky and Ursiny State that Beneš Told Them He Offered Ruthenia to Stalin in December, 1943," n.d. (Folder 53: 12)
  - "O cíli a metodách naší zahraniční práce," n.d. (Folder 53: 13)
  - "Observations by Dr. Štefan Osuský on the Draft Report by the Defence Committee Relative to the Organization and Legal Status of the Military Administration," n.d. (Folder 53: 14)
  - "Odchod Dra. Osuského z Francie," n.d. (Folder 53: 15)
  - "Odkaz domovu," n.d. (Folder 53: 16)
  - "Odpověd New Yorkskému deníku a New Yorkským Listom," n.d. (Folder 53: 17)
  - "Oriental Fatalism Versus Faith," n.d. (Folder 53: 18)
  - "Origin of Disagreement Between Beneš and Osuský," n.d. (Folder 53: 19)
  - "Origin of Inequality Among Men," n.d. (Folder 53: 20)
  - "Orthodox Church Doctrine," n.d. (Folder 53: 21)
  - "Osuský a Beneš po Mnichově," n.d. (Folder 53: 22)
  - "Osuský: His Relations with Hácha and Bonnet," n.d. (Folder 53: 23)
  - "Osuský's Stand at the Outbreak of World War I," n.d. (Folder 53: 24)
  - "Our Hope for Tomorrow," speech, n.d. (Folder 53: 25)
  - "Outstanding Psychological and Material Characteristics," n.d. (Folder 53: 26)
  - "Panslavism," n.d. (Folder 53: 27)
    Holograph and typescript (part of the Way of the Free?)
  - "La parenté d'esprit entre la France et la Tchécoslovaquie," n.d. (Folder 53: 28)
  - "The Party and Its Policy" [in Russia], n.d. (Folder 53: 29)
  - "Pastoral Letter of the Czech Catholic Churches in the Protectorate of Bohemia and Moravia," n.d. (Folder 53: 30)
  - "Peaceful Co-Existence," n.d. (Folder 53: 31)
  - "The Peasant," n.d. (Folder 53: 32)
  - "Peter Prídavok and Hubert Ripka," n.d. (Folder 53: 33)
  - "The Philosophy of Liberalism," n.d. (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - "Pisarev (1840-1868)," n.d. (Folder 54: 2)
  - "Planning," n.d. (Folder 54: 3)
  - "Poland," n.d. (Folder 54: 4)
  - "Polish-Czechoslovak Relations," n.d. (Folder 54: 5)
  - "The Polish-Czechoslovak Union and Its Implications," n.d. (Folder 54: 6)
  - "The Political Union of the East-Central European States," n.d. (Folder 54: 7)
  - "Politická a hospodářská vojna," n.d. (Folder 54: 8)
  - "Politické ciele pre domov," n.d. (Folder 54: 9)
  - "Politické vedenie," n.d. (Folder 54: 10)
  - "Poznámky k zpráve Státnej rady," n.d. (Folder 54: 11)
  - "The Prague Slavonic Congress, May 31, 1848," n.d. (Folder 54: 12)
  - "Představitel koncepce osobnosti v odboji," n.d. (Folder 54: 13)
  - "The Prescription of Lippmann," n.d. (Folder 54: 14)
  - "Present Fundamental Differences," n.d. (Folder 54: 15)
  - "The Presidency and Europe," n.d. (Folder 54: 16)
  - "President Beneš and His Government," n.d. (Folder 54: 17)
  - "President Beneš's Personal Representative in America," n.d. (Folder 54: 18)
  - "President Edvard Beneš's Amazing Confession," n.d. (Folder 54: 19)
  - "President Tomáš G. Masaryk," n.d. (Folder 54: 20)
  - "Pride" [in Russia], n.d. (Folder 54: 21)
  - "Principles of the Atlantic Declaration," n.d. (Folder 54: 22)
  - "Principles of the New Order," n.d. (Folder 54: 23)
  - "Pripomienky Dra. Osuského k zprave Politického výboru: Odpoved Státní rady na poselství presidenta republiky ze dne 22. prosince 1941," n.d. (Folder 54: 24)
  - "Le Procès de Prague" [on the Soviet-Czechoslovak economic treaty of 1952 and the anti-Semitic political trial against Slansky], n.d. (Folder 54: 25)
  - "Programme of the Fierlinger Government," n.d. (Folder 54: 26)
  - "Prolongation of the Past into the Future," n.d. (Folder 54: 27)
  - "Le protocole soviet du 23 août 1939," n.d. (Folder 54: 28)
  - "The Purport of the Soviet-Czechoslovak Alliance," n.d. (Folder 54: 29)
  - "Quinze jours avant Munich: Le président Beneš propose la cession des Sudètes," n.d. (Folder 54: 30)
  - "Quo vadis Czecho-Slovakia?" n.d. (Folder 54: 31)
  - Radio speech on Jan Masaryk's death, n.d. (Folder 54: 32)
  - "Reč demokratická ale skutky diktátorské," n.d. (Folder 54: 33)
  - "Religion," n.d. (Folder 54: 34)
  - "Religion and the Church," n.d. (Folder 54: 35)
  - "Remarks to Gringoires' article," n.d. (Folder 54: 36)
  - Review of Stephen Borsody, The Triumph of Tyranny, n.d. (Folder 54: 37)
  - Review of M. Garnett and H. F. Koeppler, A Lasting Peace, n.d. (Folder 54: 38)
  - "Rozbor Deklaracie Benešovej vlády o osude Slovenská v obnovenej Československej Republike, keby sa ona dostala v nej k moci po vítazstve Spojencov," n.d. (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - "Rule of Law Under Communist Regimes," n.d. (Folder 55: 2)
  - "Rusko a Polsko," New Yorkský Denník, n.d. (Folder 55: 3)
  - "Russian Constants," n.d. (Folder 55: 4)
  - "Russian Messianism," n.d. (Folder 55: 5)
  - "Russian Orthodox Church," n.d. (Folder 55: 6)
  - "Russian Patriotism," n.d. (Folder 55: 7)
  - "Russian Philosophers," n.d. (Folder 55: 8)
  - "Russians: A Deeper Sense of Spirituality," n.d. (Folder 55: 9)
  - "Salient Facts Pertaining to Czechoslovakia's Tragedy," n.d. (Folder 55: 10)
  - "The Second Industrial Revolution in Europe," n.d. (Folder 55: 11)
  - "Second Warsaw?" n.d. (Folder 55: 12)
  - "Le 7 mars 1936 et l'Europe Centrale," n.d. (Folder 55: 13)
    Holograph and typescript (in French)
  - "La situation économique en Allemagne," n.d. (Folder 55: 14)
  - "Skills in Management," n.d. (Folder 55: 15)
  - "The Slavophils," n.d. (Folder 55: 16)
  - "Slováci, socialisti a Národný výbor," n.d. (Folder 55: 17)
  - "Slovak Resistance," n.d. (Folder 55: 18)
  - "The Slovak Tragedy," n.d. (Folder 55: 19)
  - "Slovakia and the Czechoslovak Republic," n.d. (Folder 55: 20)
  - "Slovakia: The Model Example of the 'New Order'," n.d. (Folder 55: 21)
  - "The Slovaks," n.d. (Folder 55: 22)
  - "Slovaks in Revolt," n.d. (Folder 55: 23)
  - "The Slovaks of America," n.d. (Folder 55: 24)
  - "Slovania a Europa," n.d. (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - "Slovenky a Češky, Slováci a Češi," speech, n.d. (Folder 56: 2)
  - "Slovenské mučednictvo," n.d. (Folder 56: 3)
  - "Slovensko a Slováci," n.d. (Folder 56: 4)
  - "Slovenským spolkom v Chicagu," speech, n.d. (Folder 56: 5)
  - "Social Factors," n.d. (Folder 56: 6)
  - "Socialistická zákonnost v době intelektuálního vření," n.d. (Folder 56: 7)
  - "Socrates," n.d. (Folder 56: 8)
  - "Sovereignty Union and the Devil," n.d. (Folder 56: 9)
  - "Soviet Literature," n.d. (Folder 56: 10)
  - "The Soviet-Polish Relations," n.d. (Folder 56: 11)
  - "The Sovietization of the Bar in Captive European Countries," n.d. (Folder 56: 12)
  - Speech commemorating the birthday of T. G. Masaryk, n.d. (Folder 56: 13)
  - Speech on behalf of the Central Committee of the Council of Free Czechoslovakia, n.d. (Folder 56: 14)
  - Speech on the advantages of preferential system in Central Europe, n.d. (Folder 56: 15)
    Typescript (in French)
  - Speech on the failure of the League of Nations, n.d. (Folder 56: 16)
  - Speech on French parliamentary elections and their impact on the future of Europe, n.d. (Folder 56: 17)
  - Speech? on Hitler and the beginning of World War II, n.d. (Folder 56: 18)
    Typescript (in Czech and Slovak)
  - Speech on Slovak Christian heritage and americanism, n.d. (Folder 56: 19)
  - Speech on the history of Czechoslovakia, n.d. (Folder 56: 20)
  - Speech on the occasion of the Czechoslovak Social Democratic Party commemorative meeting, n.d. (Folder 56: 21)
  - Speech on Tito's Yugoslavia and Poland as examples of 'non-Soviet socialism', n.d. (Folder 56: 22)
    Typescript (in French and Slovak)
  - Speech to Poland, n.d. (Folder 56: 23)
  - "Stalin's Doctrine of Nationality," n.d. (Folder 56: 24)
  - "Stalin's Kampf," n.d. (Folder 56: 25)
  - "Stalin's Present Policy," n.d. (Folder 56: 26)
  - "Un statut quo illusoire," n.d. (Folder 56: 27)
  - "The Strong Will Always Help Himself," n.d. (Folder 56: 28)
  - "Subcarpathic Russia," n.d. (Folder 56: 29)
  - "A Suggestion Regarding the Teschen Controversy," n.d. (Folder 56: 30)
  - "Svoboda dnes, zítra a na věky," radio speech, n.d. (Folder 56: 31)
  - "Tchécoslovaquie et Pologne," n.d. (Folder 56: 32)
  - "They Fought Alone," n.d. (Folder 56: 33)
  - "Thorn in the Side of Europe," n.d. (Folder 56: 34)
  - "The Tragedy of Political Errors," n.d. (Folder 56: 35)
  - "Treaty," n.d. (Folder 56: 36)
  - "The Trend of Russian Mind," n.d. (Folder 56: 37)
  - "Le tribunal d'équité du professeur Strupp," n.d. (Folder 56: 38)
  - "Triumph of Western Civilization," radio broadcast, n.d. (Folder 56: 39)
  - "Truth Prevails," n.d. (Folder 56: 40)
  - "Turgenev," n.d. (Folder 56: 41)
  - "U.S. and Indo-China," n.d. (Folder 56: 42)
  - "U.S. and Soviet Russia," n.d. (Folder 56: 43)
  - "U.S., Britain and Asia," n.d. (Folder 56: 44)
  - "Ultimatum of September 1938," n.d. (Box-folder 57: 1)
  - "The United Nations and the Destiny of Western Civilization," n.d. (Folder 57: 2)
  - "The United States and Soviet Russia," n.d. (Folder 57: 3)
  - "The United States Policy Towards Europe," n.d. (Folder 57: 4)
  - "Universal Organisation," n.d. (Folder 57: 5)
  - "Ustavná švejkovina," n.d. (Folder 57: 6)
  - "Uznanie Anglie, 4/26/1940-7/6/1940," timeline, n.d. (Folder 57: 7)